教练，你好吗？
Coach, how are you doing?
Entrenador, ¿cómo va?
好吧，来自萨尔塔的 Team 10 的哈维尔·阿帕里西奥 (Javier Aparicio)，我们正在直播。
Well, Javier Aparicio for Team 10 from Salta, we are live.
Bueno, Javier Aparicio para Equipo 10 de Salta, estamos en vivo.
我想问一下你对于游戏离开的感受。
I wanted to ask you about the feeling that the game left you.
Te quería preguntar sobre la sensación que te dejó el partido.
他的决心和费用都是令人情绪化的，这似乎并不......
the resolution he had and also the fee is emotional which seems to be something that does not...
la resolución que tuvo y también la cuota es emocional que parece ser una cosa que no...
还没完，今天又加了天使的东西，你脑子里一定有各种东西，谢谢。
It doesn't end, today the Angel thing was added, there must be a mix of everything surely in your head, thank you.
No termina, hoy se sumó lo de Ángel, debe haber una mezcla de todo seguramente en tu cabeza, gracias.
晚安。
Good night.
Buenas noches.
上半场比赛形势复杂。
The game was complicated in the first half.
El partido fue complicado en el primer tiempo.
虽然我认为到目前为止
although I think that up to the minute
aunque creo que hasta el minuto
30 我们比智利好得多，上半场结束后我们没有......
30 we were much better than Chile, after the end of the first half we didn't...
30 fuimos bastante superior a Chile, después el final del primer tiempo no...
情况不太好，他们甚至还有进球的情况。
It wasn't good, they even had a goal situation.
no fue bueno, ellos incluso tuvieron una situación de gol.
嗯，一如既往，你可以在中场休息时在那里进行交谈，以便能够纠正，我认为球队
and well, as always, you can be there at halftime to be able to talk to be able to correct and I think that the team
y bueno como siempre se puede estar el entretiempo para poder hablar para poder corregir y creo que el equipo
在下半场的第一场比赛中，他出场了
In the first play of the second half he came out with
en la primera jugada del segundo tiempo salió con
多一个局点
with one more game point
con un punto más de juego
最后我认为结果是公平的，我们赢了。
In the end I think the result is fair, we won well.
Al final creo que el resultado es justo, ganamos bien.
夜晚非常美好，就像最近发生的那样。
and the night is very good, as has been happening lately.
y la noche es muy buena, como viene sucediendo últimamente.
对于每个人，对于那些能看到他眼睛的人来说，这是一种巨大的、当之无愧的喜悦。
A huge and well-deserved joy for everyone, for the people who could see his eyes.
Una alegría enorme y merecido para todos, para la gente que pudo ver a sus ojos.
球员们，因为我们无法与他们一起庆祝，我认为今天是一个时刻
players since we have not been able to celebrate with them I think today was a moment
jugadores ya que no hemos podido festejar con ellos creo que hoy era era un momento
赛后很好，特别是，很高兴一如既往地感谢他
good after the game especially and good to thank him as always and
bueno después del partido sobre todo y bueno agradecerle como siempre y
我们已经告诉了安赫尔我们要说的一切，我刚刚向他道别，然后……
And we already told Ángel everything we had to say, I just said goodbye to him and...
y a Ángel ya le dijimos todo lo que teníamos que decirle, me acabo de despedir de él y...
告诉他，他的大门对他在国家队想要的任何东西都是敞开的，因为只要我们在那里，我想......
Tell him that his doors are open for whatever he wants in the national team, since as long as we are there, I imagine that...
decirle que tiene las puertas abiertas para lo que quiera en la selección, desde que mientras estemos nosotros, imagino que...
我们不在场的那天也是如此，因为他是这支球队、这个国家的传奇人物。
That will also be the case the day we are not there because he is a legend of this team, of this country.
que también será así el día que no estemos nosotros porque es leyenda de esta selección, de este país.
快乐的。
happy.
contento.
莱昂内尔，晚上好，这里是 Disports 的法昆多·桑切斯 (Facundo Sánchez)，就在您的左边，下面。
Lionel, good evening, here is Facundo Sánchez for Disports, here to your left, below.
Lionel, buenas noches, acá Facundo Sánchez para Disports, acá a tu izquierda, abajo.
祝贺胜利。
Congratulations on the victory.
Felicitaciones por la victoria.
我想问一下您对于这些变化，尤其是尼科·冈萨雷斯和麦卡利斯特的离开，您是否有任何不适。
I want to ask you about the changes, especially the departure of Nico González and Macalister, if you have any discomfort.
Te quiero preguntar por los cambios, sobre todo por la salida de Nico González y de Macalister, si tiene alguna molestia.
你对迪巴拉的进球感到多么高兴，他不得不再次增加上场时间，距离他在决赛中打入最后一粒进球已经过去两年了。
And how happy you were in particular for Dybala's goal, he had to add minutes again, it had been two years since he had converted the last one in the very final.
y cuánto te alegró en particular el gol de Dybala, le tocó volver a sumar minutos, hacía dos años que no convertía el último en la finalísima.
您对个性化也感到多么高兴。
How happy you were also in the personalization.
Cuánto te alegró también en lo personalizo.
谢谢。
Gracias.
好吧，我们仍然不知道他们怎么样。
Well, we still don't know how they are.
Bueno, todavía no sabemos cómo están.
从逻辑上讲，他们出来是因为他们两者都有。
Logically, they came out because they had both.
Lógicamente han salido porque tenían ambos.
不舒服，我们会看看他们是否可以参加下一场比赛。
discomfort and we'll see if they can be in the next game.
molestias y ya veremos si podrán estar en el partido siguiente.
所以不，今天很匆忙。
So no, it's rushed today.
Así que no, es apresurado hoy.
还有保罗...
And Paul...
Y Pablo...
一切都一点点，快乐，还有……作为一名教练……
a little bit of everything, joy and that... as a coach that...
un poco de todo, alegría y ese... como entrenador esa...
他不能和我们一起参加杯赛，感觉很糟糕。
ugly feeling that he couldn't be with us in the Cup.
sensación fea de que no haya podido estar con nosotros en la Copa.
这就是足球的本质，球员
That's what this football thing has, it's a player who
es lo que tiene esto del fútbol, es un jugador que
当它好的时候就会产生影响，它可以给我们带来很多东西。
that when it is good it makes a difference, it can give us a lot of things.
que cuando está bien marca diferencia, nos puede aportar un montón de cosas.
由于技术决定，最重要的是因为美洲杯名单开始时
due to technical decisions and above all because when the start of the Copa América list
por decisiones técnicas y sobre todo porque cuando el inicio de la lista de la Copa América
我们无法承担风险，但我们必须承担
We were not in a position to take risks and we had to take
no estábamos en condiciones de arriesgar y hemos tenido que tomar
决定不来了...
The decision not to come and...
La decisión de que no venga y...
但你必须做出回应的唯一方法就是做你今天所做的事情。
But the only way you have to respond is by doing what you did today.
Pero la única manera que se tiene que responder es haciendo lo que hizo hoy.
如有空闲，请根据需要输入尽可能多的分钟数。
being available, entering as many minutes as necessary.
estando a disposición, entrando en los minutos que sea necesario.
进球，不仅是进球，还为球队贡献了很多东西。
scoring the goal and not only scoring the goal but contributing a lot of things to the team.
haciendo el gol y no sólo haciendo el gol sino aportando un montón de cosas al equipo.
在和平中、在康复中、在玩耍中，我想……
in peace, in recovery, in play, I think...
en el paz, en la recuperación, en el juego, creo que...
当一个球员有这种态度并且最重要的是他只属于他的类别
when a player has this attitude and on top of that he is in his category alone
cuando un jugador tiene esta actitud y encima es de la categoría de él solo
我们仍然要感谢他，说实话，我们为他感到高兴。
It remains to thank him and we are happy for him, honestly.
resta agradecerle y estamos contentos por él, la verdad.
晚上好，莱昂内尔。
Good evening, Leonel.
Buenas noches, Leonel.
红色电台的古斯塔沃·亚罗克。
Gustavo Yarroch for Radio La Red.
Gustavo Yarroch para Radio La Red.
我想问你国家队下半程
I wanted to ask you if the second half of the national team
Quería preguntarte si el segundo tiempo de la selección
这很接近你想要的理想。
It was close to the ideal you want.
estuvo cerca del ideal que pretendés.
布埃诺。
Bueno.
事实上，这些简单的问题总是在比赛结束后被问到，也许他们不会。
The truth is that these quick questions are always asked after the game is over, maybe they won't.
La verdad es que siempre estas preguntas así rápidas después que termine el partido a lo mejor no lo
听起来很好，你不去想，但它被播放了
It sounds very good and you don't think about it, but it was played
suena muy bien y no lo pensas, pero sí que se jugó
嗯，总有一些地方需要纠正，但是，是的，确实如此......
Well, there is always something to correct, but yes, it is true that...
Bien, siempre hay algo para corregir, pero sí, es verdad que...
通过对手可以离开你的东西，球队在对方场上，快速收回球，创造局面
through what the rival can leave you, the team was in the opposite field, recovered the ball quickly, generated situations
mediante lo que el rival te puede dejar, el equipo estuvo en campo contrario, recuperó rápido la pelota, generó situaciones
从这个意义上说，下半场已经完成。
In that sense the second half is complete.
En ese sentido es completo el segundo tiempo.
我无法告诉你它在我们玩过的游戏中处于什么水平，但是
I couldn't tell you if it is at what level it is among those we have played but
no sabría decirte si está en qué nivel está de los que hemos jugado pero
最后，当你在竞争对手的领域尝试时，它和往常一样
In the end it is the same as always when you are there in the rival field trying
al final es lo de siempre cuando estás ahí en campo rival intentar
精确，当这些人精确时，通常会以进球或进球的情况结束
be precise and when these guys are precise it usually ends in a goal or goal situation
ser preciso y cuando estos chicos son precisos normalmente termina en situación de gol o gol
当不需要它们时，我们必须再次恢复它以再次攻击。
and when they are not necessary we have to recover it again to attack again.
y cuando no son precisos la tenemos que volver a recuperar para volver a atacar.
就是这个想法。
That's the idea.
Esa es la idea.
莱昂内尔、奥克塔维奥·佩特里奇担任维克多·雨果的报告员。
Leonel, Octavio Petrich for rapporteurs with Víctor Hugo.
Leonel, Octavio Petrich para relatores con Víctor Hugo.
两个短的。
Two short ones.
Dos cortitas.
在 Lisandra Martínez 的请求评估中，在 Andarivel 上看到它也许是一种战术新奇。
in a request evaluation by Lisandra Martínez, perhaps a tactical novelty seeing it on the Andarivel.
en una evaluación de pido de Lisandra Martínez, quizá una novedad táctica viéndolo sobre la Andarivel.
还有奥塔门迪，他在美洲杯上不一定要首发，今天他作为队长证明了自己的有效性以及在小组中的优势。
and also from Otamendi who in the Copa América did not have to be a starter and today he demonstrates his validity as well as his ascendancy in the group by being captain.
y también de Otamendi que en la Copa América no le tocó por ahí ser titular y hoy demuestra la vigencia además de la ascendencia en el grupo siendo capitán.
谢谢。
Gracias.
嗯，这就是我们或多或少所说的......
Well, that's what we more or less said...
Bueno, es lo que más o menos dijimos...
我们和巴勃罗一起做了一个决定，在这种情况下，太田的决定
with Pablo that we made a decision, in this case the decision that Ota
con Pablo que tomamos decisión, en este caso la decisión de que Ota
他不必参加杯赛，这纯粹是足球决定。
He didn't have to play in the Cup, it was a purely football decision.
No le haya tocado jugar en la Copa, fue una decisión meramente futbolística.
今天我们决定他必须上场，因为左后卫
and today we decided that he had to play because the left back
y hoy decidimos que tenía que jugar porque el lateral izquierdo
理论上我们不会用到它，我们会让 Nico González 和 Lissandro 的车在那里为我们提供......
Theoretically we were going to use it little, we were going to have Nico González and Lissandro's cart there to give us...
Teóricamente lo íbamos a usar poco, íbamos a tener el carrico Nico González y Lissandro ahí nos daba...
他给了我们一个很好的传球，我们希望能够与这三个人一起比赛。
He gave us a good pass and we wanted to be able to play with all three.
Nos daba buen pase y queríamos oportuno que podamos jugar con los tres.
三名球员而不是三名中后卫
the three players not three center backs
los tres jugadores no tres centrales por
因为最后利桑德罗作为边锋防守，纳韦尔也作为边锋防守，也就是说，我们用四人防守，但我们确实尝试了
because in the end Lisandro defended as a winger and Nahuel also defended as a winger, that is, we defended with four but we did try
porque al final Lisandro defendía de lateral y Nahuel de lateral también o sea defendíamos con cuatro pero sí intentar
我认为利桑德罗的传球在不属于他的位置上是一场精彩的比赛。
I think Lisandro's pass was a good game in a position that is not his.
El pase de Lisandro creo que hizo un buen partido en una posición que no es no es la suya
我们已经知道，当我们号召他们投入事业时，他们总是在那时
and happy and another we already know that when we call them to the cause it is always then
y contento y otra ya sabemos que cuando los llamamos a la causa está siempre entonces
这就是国家队需要的，也是球队需要的。
That's what the national team needs and what the team needs.
Eso es lo que necesita la selección y lo que necesita el equipo.
吉安卢卡·奥达佐 (Gianluca Odazzo) 为《自由收复失地运动》拍摄。
Gianluca Odazzo for Via Libre Reconquista.
Gianluca Odazzo para Vía Libre Reconquista.
恭喜你取得胜利，距离迈阿密决赛对阵哥伦比亚仅仅过去了53天。
Congratulations on the victory, just 53 days have passed since the Miami final against Colombia.
Felicitaciones por la victoria, apenas 53 días pasaron de la final de Miami contra Colombia.
随着世界杯的临近，球队已经重返赛场。
The team is back competing, already with the World Cup on the horizon.
El equipo de vuelta compitiendo, ya con el Mundial en el horizonte.
但是你在哪里装载燃料、能量......
but where do you load the fuel, the energy to...
pero ¿dónde cargas el combustible, la energía para...
以这支阿根廷队始终设定的高标准来应对这些挑战。
face these challenges with the high bar that this Argentine team always sets.
afrontar estos desafíos con la vara tan alta que deja este equipo argentino siempre.
谢谢。
Gracias.
嗯，我……我是说，那个……
Well, I... I mean, the...
Bueno, yo... o sea, la...
我们通过与他们的竞争来装载燃料
We load the fuel through the competition that they
cargamos el combustible a través de la competición de que ellos
让他们明白他们必须竞争、必须参加比赛并不困难，因为如果其他人不来，他们就必须参加比赛。
It is not very difficult to make them understand that they have to compete and they have to play because if someone else does not come and
no es muy difícil hacerla entender a ellos que tienen que competir y tienen que jugar porque si no viene otro y
并抢占了他的位置。
and grabs his position.
y le agarra el puesto.
这是我们的座右铭，我相信
That is a motto that we have and that I believe
Eso es un lema que tenemos y que creo que
对于像阿根廷这样的球队来说，情况一定如此。
That has to be like that in a team like Argentina.
que tiene que ser así en una selección como la Argentina.
你可以选择，好吧，我还没明白这个消息。
You can choose and well, I haven't understood the message.
Podés elegir y bueno, yo no he entendido el mensaje.
之后他们继续比赛。
and they continue competing afterwards.
y siguen compitiendo después.
最近的结果是积极的，这很有帮助。
The result lately has been positive and that helps.
El resultado últimamente está siendo positivo y eso ayuda.
在不乐观的日子里，我们也需要以同样的方式。
The day that is not positive we need to be in the same way.
El día que no sea positivo necesitamos estar de la misma manera.
蒂内尔，在这里。
Tionel, here.
Tionel, aquí.
晚安。
Good night.
Buenas noches.
埃尔南·西斯托 (Hernán Sisto) 在 Diez por Radio 为 Doble Amarillo 创作。
Hernán Sisto for Doble Amarillo on Diez por Radio.
Hernán Sisto para Doble Amarillo de Diez por Radio.
我想问你...
I want to ask you...
Te quiero preguntar...
这支球队已经给出了充足的证据，即使没有莱奥、没有梅西，也能踢球，今天迪马利亚也缺席了。
This team had already given ample evidence that even without Leo, without Messi, it could play, today Di María was also missing.
Este equipo ya había dado sobradas muestras de que incluso sin Leo, sin Messi podía jugar, hoy faltaba Di María también.
但名单上有很多中场前锋的替代者，有很多名字，马蒂·索布尔（Mati Soble）被添加了，嗯......
but you had a lot of replacement on the list from midfield forward, many names out there, Mati Soble who were added, well...
pero tú tuviste mucho recambio en la lista de mitad de cancha hacia adelante, muchos nombres por ahí, Mati Soble que se fueron sumando, bueno...
朱利亚诺·西蒙尼（Juliano Simeone），加纳乔（Garnacho）今天进入，他再次表现得非常好。
Juliano Simeone, Garnacho entered today and again he did very well.
Juliano Simeone, hoy ingresó Garnacho y otra vez lo hizo muy bien.
这对你来说有多重要？
How important is that to you?
¿Qué tan importante es eso para ustedes?
我说，名字继续被添加到这个选择的新窝中。
I say, that names continue to be added to this new litter of this selection.
digo, que se sigan sumando nombres a esta nueva camada de esta selección.
该团队继续以同样的方式做出反应，并且从外部看该团队一如既往地团结。
and that the team continues to respond in the same way and that the group looks from the outside as united as ever.
y que el equipo siga respondiendo igualmente de la misma forma y que el grupo se vea desde afuera tan unido como siempre.
选择始终需要的观点很重要
The point of view that the selection always needs is important
es importante el punto de vista que la selección siempre necesita
我并不是说替换，因为当球队表现良好时，不会，但确实需要......
I'm not saying replacement because when the team is good, no, but it does need...
No digo recambio porque cuando el equipo está bien, no, pero sí que necesita que...
不要让任何人放松，然后他的鼓励，如果一名球员很好，为什么不给他打电话呢？
let no one relax and then his encouragement and if a player is fine, why not call him?
que nadie se relaje y luego su estímulo y si un jugador está bien, ¿por qué no llamarlo?
始终是我们认为我们可能缺乏的位置。
Always a position that we believe we may lack.
Siempre una posición que creemos que nos puede faltar.
谢谢！
¡Gracias!
在这种情况下，我们没有 Leo，Angel 也不会在那里。
In this case we didn't have Leo, Ángel won't be there.
En este caso no teníamos a Leo, Ángel no va a estar.
我们需要看到球员处于球队需要的位置。
We need to see players in positions where the team needs them.
necesitamos ver jugadores en posiciones donde el equipo por ahí necesite.
我们将在力所能及的范围内为您提供机会。
and to the extent we can we will give you the opportunity.
y en la medida que podamos le vamos a dar la oportunidad.
今天当然轮到亚历杭德罗了……
Today it was Alejandro's turn, surely...
Hoy le tocó a Alejandro, seguramente...
有些人会认为他之前可以进入，也可以不进入，但我们决定他在那一刻进入，因为
Some will think that he could have entered before or not but well we decided that he would enter at that moment because
algunos pensarán que podría haber entrado antes o no pero bueno decidimos que entre en ese momento porque
我们需要他融入球队的比赛方式。
We need him to get into the team's way of playing.
Necesitamos que entre en la manera de jugar del equipo.
今天他明白了一切，我一切都很好。
Today he understood everything and everything was fine with me.
Hoy entendió todo y yo todo bien.
当我必须转弯时我会达到顶峰，当我必须刹车时我会刹车。
I peak when I have to corner and brake when I have to brake.
Pico cuando tenía que picar y freno cuando tenía que frenar.
他是一位可以为我们做出很多贡献的球员，但要冷静，因为我们需要带上他
and he is a player who can contribute a lot to us, but calmly because we need to take him
y es un jugador que nos puede aportar mucho, pero con calma porque necesitamos llevarlo
渐渐地，他将不得不像其他孩子一样玩耍，这会给我们带来快乐。
little by little and he will have to play like the other kids and it will give us joy.
de a poco y ya le tocará jugar como a los demás chicos y nos dará alegrías.
莱昂内尔，晚安。
Leonel, good night.
Leonel, buenas noches.
来自美洲、图库曼和普拉塔广播电台的 Daniel Urueña。
Daniel Urueña from América, Tucumán and Radio del Plata.
Daniel Urueña de América, Tucumán y Radio del Plata.
祝贺胜利。
Congratulations on the victory.
Felicitaciones por la victoria.
阿根廷队在这场比赛中对其他对手取得了显着的优势，今天智利队即将到来......
The Argentine team is achieving notable supremacy over the rest of the rivals in this tie, today Chile is coming...
La selección argentina está logrando una supremacía notable sobre el resto de los rivales en esta eliminatoria, hoy Chile se viene...
或者说他在上半场进行了一些抵抗，下半场阿根廷就反超了他。
or he put up some resistance in the first half, in the second half Argentina overtook him.
o puso algo de resistencia en el primer tiempo, en el segundo Argentina lo pasó por arriba.
如果未来可能有其他名字的话，拥有如此高的稳定性和让团队如此充满活力有什么好处呢？
What is the merit of having so much consistency and having the team so oiled and in the future if there may be other names?
¿Cuál es el mérito de tener tanta regularidad y tener tan aceitado al equipo y en un futuro si puede haber otros nombres?
与那些正在寻找未来球队更新的人不同。
different from those who are, looking for what the renewal of what the future team could be.
distintos a los que están, mirando para lo que es la renovación de lo que puede ser la futura selección.
原则上我不认为与其他人有那么大的优越性，我确实这么说。
In principle I don't think there is that much superiority with the rest, I really say that.
En principio no creo que haya tanta superioridad con el resto, de verdad lo digo.
我认为这非常相似，是的，确实如此......
I think this is very similar and yes, it is true that...
creo que es esto muy parejo y que sí, es verdad que...
我们正处于一个美好的时刻，但足球很奇怪，在任何时候它都可以
We are in a good moment but football is very strange and at any moment it can
estamos en un buen momento pero el fútbol es muy extraño y en cualquier momento te puede
他们可以让你就位，然后我们继续一场一场的比赛。
They can put you in your place, then we continue game by game.
te pueden poner en tu sitio, entonces seguimos partido a partido.
如果有新的名字，那么，基于团队的需要，基于职位。
And if there will be new names, well, based on what the team needs, based on the positions.
Y si habrá nuevos nombres, bueno, en base a lo que el equipo necesite, en base a las posiciones.
我们总是期待见到球员，因为我们带来的名单上有很多优秀的球员
We always look forward to seeing players because there are a lot of good ones on the list we have brought
siempre nos quedamos con ganas de ver jugadores porque hay un montón pero bueno en la lista de la que es hemos traído
还有四名足球运动员，我们被排除在外会很伤心
four more footballers that it hurts us to leave out and
cuatro futbolistas más que nos duele dejar afuera y
而且没有计划需要更多，因为将这些孩子排除在外并不容易。
And there is no plan to need many more because it is not easy to leave those kids out.
y tampoco es plan de necesitar a muchos más porque no es fácil dejar a esos chicos afuera.
尽我们所能。
to the extent we can.
en la medida que podamos.
我们不想看到一些球员。
We haven't been left wanting to see some players.
No hemos quedado con la gana de ver a algunos jugadores.
谁参加了电话会议，例如瓦莱尔迪，他度过了一个美好的赛季并且......
who were in the call, the case of Valerdi, for example, who had been having a good season and...
que estaban en la convocatoria, el caso de Valerdi, por ejemplo, que venía cuajando una buena temporada y...
由于受伤我们不能带他来，我不希望他来这里，因为他......
and we couldn't bring him because of the injury, I wouldn't have liked him to be here because he is...
y no lo pudimos traer por la lesión, que no hubiera gustado que esté acá porque es...
我们相信他是一个能够为我们和其他在球队需要时到来的人做出贡献的男孩。
He is a boy who we believe is in a position to contribute to us and others who will come as the team needs it.
Es un chico que creemos que está en condiciones de aportarnos y otros más que van a venir en medida que el equipo lo necesite.
莱昂内拉（Leonella）是米特广播电台的巴勃罗·菲利皮尼（Pablo Filippini）。
Leonella here, Pablo Filippini from Radio Miter.
Leonella aquí, Pablo Filippini de Radio Mitre.
我想问你为什么总是强调
I wanted to ask you why you always highlighted
Quería preguntarte por qué siempre remarcaste
伊巴拉不邀请他参加美洲杯也许是一个痛苦的决定。
that perhaps it was a painful decision by Ibala not to call him to the Copa América.
que quizás fue una decisión dolorosa aquella de Ibala de no haberlo convocado a la Copa América.
它怎么样？
How was it?
¿Cómo fue?
告诉他我将穿上 10 号球衣，这代表着阿根廷队的一切，如果你们进行个人谈话，你会如何......
Tell him that I was going to wear the number 10 shirt with everything that the Argentine team means, if you had an individual talk, how would you...
contarle que iba a usar la camiseta número 10 con todo lo que significa la selección argentina, si tuviste una charla individual, cómo se lo...
你说，你也想知道瓦伦丁·卡斯特拉诺（Valentín Castellano），他这些天是怎么看待这件事的。
you said and also wonder about Valentín Castellano, how he has seen it these days.
manifestaste y preguntarte también por lo de Valentín Castellano, cómo lo ha visto en estos días.
如果这名球员让你感到惊讶，考虑到这是他第一次征召入队。
And if it is a player who has surprised you something, taking into account that it is his first call-up.
y si es un jugador que te ha sorprendido algo, teniendo en cuenta que es su primera convocatoria.
好吧，对于巴勃罗，我会诚实地告诉你，我们没有谈论给他 10，我们决定给他，然后......
Well, with Pablo, I'll be honest with you, we didn't talk about giving him the 10, we decided to give it to him and...
Bueno, con Pablo, te soy sincero, no hablamos de darle la 10, decidimos dársela y...
我们没有告诉他你要使用 10 号，我认为他是拥有 10 号的足球运动员。
and we didn't tell him you were going to use the 10, I think he is the footballer to have the 10.
y no le dijimos vas a usar la 10, creo que es el futbolista para tener la 10.
然后说服自己的同伴告诉他，他就是那个必须带走她的人。
and then convincing his own companions to tell him that he was the one who had to take her.
y después convencimiento de sus propios compañeros para decirle que es él el que la tenía que llevar.
我们没有告诉他，我们只是整理了清单以及如何使用它。
We didn't tell him, we just put together the list and how to use it.
No le dijimos, simplemente armamos la lista y cómo hay que usar.
10，在这个例子中是11，我已经知道力拓会接受它，我们做出了这个决定。
10 and in this case 11, I already knew that Rio was going to take it, we made that decision.
la 10 y en este caso la 11, ya sabía que la iba a llevar Río, tomamos esa decisión.
他接受了，这说明了很多很多，因为那件衬衫
and he accepted it and that says a lot, a lot, because that shirt
y él la aceptó y eso habla un montón, un montón, porque esa camiseta
不幸的是，我们让她伤心了，而穿着她确实应该是一种恭维，但是
Unfortunately we make her sad when it really should be a compliment to wear her but
lamentablemente nosotros la hacemos pesar cuando realmente tendría que ser un halago llevarla pero
也许在这种情况下必须带走她的人可能是一个小男孩，不，他不会
Maybe the one who had to take her in this case could have been a young boy, no, he wouldn't have
a lo mejor al que la tenga que llevar en este caso puede haber sido un chico joven no no hubiera
我不会喜欢它，我们决定让巴勃罗接受它，因为他有足够的等级制度来拥有它。
I wouldn't have liked it and we decided to let Pablo take it because he has enough hierarchy to have it.
no hubiera gustado y decidimos que la lleve Pablo porque tiene suficiente jerarquía para tenerla.
瓦伦丁·卡斯特拉诺 我们一直在跟踪他，他当时正在打电话，而不是
and valentín castellano well we have been following him he was in a call and not
y valentín castellano bueno lo venimos siguiendo estuvo en una convocatoria y no
最终他没有来，他是一位有趣的球员，他的动作很好。
In the end he didn't come and he is an interesting player, he has good movements.
Al final no vino y es un jugador interesante, tiene buenos movimientos.
对角线有支持，他是一名可以给我们带来东西的足球运动员。
Diagonales has support, he is a footballer who can give us things.
Apoyos tiene Diagonales, es un futbolista que nos puede aportar cosas.
好吧，它已经度过了最初的几分钟，并且它将永远取决于
and well it has had its first minutes and it will always depend on
y bueno ha tenido sus primeros minutos y dependerá siempre de
正如团队常说的那样，每次通话都会满足您的需求
each call for whatever you need, as the team always says
cada convocatoria de lo que necesite como siempre digo el equipo
在这种情况下，他有必要来，他正在贡献自己的东西。
and in this case it was necessary for him to come and he is contributing his things.
y en este caso hacía falta de que venga y está aportando sus cosas.
莱昂内尔在这里。
Leonel here.
Leonel aquí.
Jornada de Mendoza 报纸的法比安·加尔迪 (Fabián Galdi) 祝贺胜利。
Fabián Galdi from the newspaper Jornada de Mendoza, congratulations on the victory.
Fabián Galdi del diario Jornada de Mendoza, felicitaciones por el triunfo.
因为选择仍然处于恩典状态，而且它还必须做......
because the selection is still in a state of grace and it also has to do...
porque la selección sigue en un estado de gracia y tiene que ver también...
真实的身体和球员如何与这个想法相结合。
how the authentic body and the players are consubstantiated with that idea.
cómo el cuerpo auténtico y los jugadores están consustanciados con esa idea.
但我想让你退出今天的比赛只是为了一件事。
but I wanted to take you out of today's game simply for one thing.
pero te quería sacar del partido de hoy simplemente por una cosa.
作为一名记者和居住在该国内陆地区的人们。
as a journalist and people who live in the interior of the country.
como periodista y gente que habito en el interior del país.
剩下的预选赛还有机会回归吗？
Is there any chance in the rest of the qualifiers that you can return?
¿Hay alguna posibilidad en el resto de las eliminatorias que se pueda volver?
前往布宜诺斯艾利斯以外的体育场。
to stadiums other than those in Buenos Aires.
a otros estadios que no sean los de Buenos Aires.
是的，我想是的。
Yes, I think so.
Sí, yo creo que sí.
我不会决定我们要去哪里比赛，以防万一。
I don't decide where we are going to play, just in case.
No decido yo dónde vamos a jugar, por las dudas.
我必须做出决定，我们在我家旁边玩。
I would have to decide, we play next to my house.
Yo tendría que decidir, jugamos al lado de mi casa.
我真的告诉​​你，我不是决定者，而且我......
I'm really telling you, I'm not the one who decides and I...
de verdad te lo digo, no soy yo el que decido y a mi me...
他告诉我让我们在那边打球吧，这对我来说总是很棒，我很想去打球
He tells me let's play on that side and it always seems great to me and I would love to go play
me dice vamos a jugar en tal lado y me parece bárbaro siempre y me encantaría ir a jugar a
到我们去过的国家的内陆地区。
to the interior of the country that we have gone to.
al interior del país que hemos ido.
我希望，我希望下次约会我们可以去。
And I hope, I hope on the next date we can go.
Y ojalá, ojalá en la siguiente fecha podamos ir.
如果我能坚强，从这里我告诉你我会的。
If I can be strong, from here I tell you that I will.
Si yo puedo ser fuerte, desde acá te digo que lo haré.
我们也会尝试进去，但没有......
We will try to go inside too but no...
intentaremos ir al interior también pero no...
这不取决于我，也许如果我说些什么，也许我可以贡献一些东西，但原则上我总是
It doesn't depend on me, maybe if I say something it might be that I can contribute something but in principle I always
no depende de mí, a lo mejor si digo algo puede ser que pueda aportar algo pero en principio siempre
有些问题我不在那里讨论。
There are some issues that I don't go into there.
Hay unas cuestiones que yo ahí no entro.
有时人们在布宜诺斯艾利斯踢球有很多目的，最重要的是
that there are times when people play in Buenos Aires for a lot of things and above all
que hay veces que se juega en Buenos Aires por un montón de cosas y sobre todo
第一场比赛将在布宜诺斯艾利斯进行，这是事实，对我们来说这很舒服。
The first game will be played in Buenos Aires, that is true, for us it is comfortable.
el primer partido jugarlo en Buenos Aires, eso sí es verdad, para nosotros es cómodo.
因为去布宜诺斯艾利斯训练然后你必须赶飞机就像在玩
because getting to Buenos Aires to train then you have to catch a plane is like practically playing
porque llegar a Buenos Aires a entrenar después tienes que agarrar un avión es como prácticamente jugar
我在外面做了什么，但我认为下一个电话首先是......
what I did away from home, but the next call I think is first in...
que hacía fuera de casa, pero la siguiente convocatoria creo que es primero en...
在委内瑞拉，如果我没记错的话，然后我们在这里比赛，如果我们能发挥一些力量的话，那可能会是这样。
In Venezuela, if I'm not mistaken and then we play here, it could be that if we make some strength.
en Venezuela, si no me equivoco y después jugamos acá, podría ser que si hacemos algo de fuerza.
你想要哪里？
Where would you like it?
¿Dónde te gustaría?
会在哪里呢？
Where would it be?
¿Dónde sería?
门多萨？
¿Mendoza?
门多萨，图库曼。
Mendoza, Tucumán.
我对罗萨里奥感兴趣，它距离我家 30 公里。
I would be interested in Rosario, it is 30 kilometers from my house.
A mí me interesaría Rosario, está a 30 kilómetros de mi casa.
就是这样，我的家人。
That's it, my family.
Así va, mi familia.
但是，嘿，我们真的要做点什么。
But hey, we're going to do something, really.
Pero bueno, algo vamos a hacer, de verdad.
莱昂内尔，你好吗？
Leonel, how are you doing?
Leonel, ¿cómo te va?
尼古拉斯·梅 (Nicolás May) 效力于 Cadena 3 和 Central Deportiva。
Nicolás May for Cadena 3 and Central Deportiva.
Nicolás May para Cadena 3 y la Central Deportiva.
别忘了圣达菲，那里比较近。
Don't forget Santa Fe, it's relatively close there.
No te olvides de Santa Fe, por ahí te queda relativamente cerquita.
有两个问题，昨天你说这是一次有点不舒服的双人约会，很多球员都变了
two questions, yesterday you had said that it was a somewhat uncomfortable double date, many players who changed
dos consultas, ayer habías dicho que era una doble fecha un tanto incómoda, muchos jugadores que cambiaban
俱乐部、训练、季前赛从几天或几周来看都不是最好的。
club, training, the preseason that was not the best in terms of days or weeks.
de club, entrenamientos, la pretemporada que por ahí no fue de la mejor en cuanto a los días o las semanas.
美洲杯之后。
after the Copa América.
tras la Copa América.
您对这次演讲以及哥伦比亚有何评价？
What evaluation do you get from this presentation and fundamentally Colombia?
¿Qué evaluación sacás de esta presentación y fundamentalmente Colombia?
决赛刚刚打完，我认为这是一支球队，我不知道它是否与阿根廷处于同一水平，但它正在经历一个美好的时刻。
The final was played a little while ago and it is a team that I think is, I don't know if it is at the same level as Argentina, but it is going through a good moment.
que hace poquito se jugó la final y es un seleccionado que creo que está, no sé si a la altura de Argentina, pero que va atravesando un buen momento.
这场胜利、这场比赛对于哥伦比亚队登顶是必要的吗？
Was this victory, this game, necessary to get to the top with Colombia?
¿Hacía falta esta victoria, este juego para llegar bien arriba con Colombia?
好吧，我们谈论这些日期是在物理层面上......
Well, what we are talking about these dates is that on a physical level...
Bueno, lo que hablamos de estas fechas es que a nivel físico...
从技术和时间上来说，球员们的表现都恰到好处。
Technically and minutes the players arrived just right.
técnico y de minutos los jugadores llegaban justo.
下半场三十多分钟后可见，双方力量相当。
It was seen that after the thirty-odd minute of the second half the forces were fair.
Se ha visto que después del minuto treinta y pico del segundo tiempo las fuerzas eran justas.
好吧，这些事情总是发生在九月，现在我们要去一个地方
and well, these things always happen in September and now we will go to a place that
y bueno siempre en septiembre pasa estas cosas y ahora iremos a un lugar que
天气太热了，我们在不适合我的时间玩，但是嘿，这就像去
It's so hot that we play at a time that shouldn't be for me, but hey, this is like going to
que hace muchísimo calor que jugamos a un horario que para mí no tendría que ser pero bueno esto es como ir a
不辜负
not to live up to
a no ir a la altura
好吧，这就是他们当时决定玩的游戏，我们将在那里玩一场游戏
and well that's what they have decided to play at that time and we will play a game there
y bueno es lo que hay han decidido jugar en ese horario y y allí iremos un partido
非常困难，我们会尽力带来好的结果
very difficult and we will try to do our best to bring a good result
difícilísimo e intentaremos hacer lo mejor para para traer un buen resultado
认为哥伦比亚是一支非常优秀的球队。
thinking that Colombia is a very good team.
pensando que Colombia es un muy buen equipo.
丹尼尔，你好吗？
Daniel, how are you doing?
Daniel, ¿cómo te va?
晚安。
Good night.
Buenas noches.
德国 RTS Medios Santa Fe 的 Germán Lucero。
Germán Lucero for RTS Medios Santa Fe.
Germán Lucero para RTS Medios Santa Fe.
你刚才提到了衬衫 10。
You just made reference to shirt 10.
Recién hiciste referencia a la camiseta 10.
11号你说你已经知道这会是为了Shio
and on the 11th you said that you already knew it was going to be for Shio
y sobre la 11 dijiste que ya sabían que iba a ser para Shio
为什么是帕拉吉奥？
Why Paragio?
¿Por qué Paragio?
论点是什么？
What is the argument?
¿Cuál es el argumento?
另外，既然你谈到了罗萨里奥……
Also, since you talked about Rosario...
Además, ya que hablaste de Rosario...
这件球衣在罗萨里奥身上有着悠久的历史，在迪玛利亚之前，在马克西罗德里格斯之前。
A shirt that has a lot of history with Rosario, before Di María, before Maxi Rodríguez.
Una camiseta que tiene mucha historia con Rosario, antes Di María, antes Maxi Rodríguez.
嗯，我想他们同意了。
Well, I think they agreed.
Bueno, creo que se pusieron de acuerdo ellos.
也就是说，迪玛利亚让他去抢吉奥的声音，吉奥说抢，那就是……
In other words, Di María told him to grab Gio's voice and Gio said the grab, that is...
O sea, que Di María le dijo agarrar la voz a Gio y Gio dijo el agarro, o sea...
就是这么简单。
It's that simple.
Así de simple.
是的，没问题。
Yes, no problem.
Sí, no hay problema.
只是有时候我们把一些事情看得太重要了...
It's just that sometimes we give too much importance to things that...
Es que le damos a veces demasiada importancia a cosas que...
一件足球球衣和...
A soccer jersey and...
Una camiseta de fútbol y...
尽管它有一个令人难以置信的故事，但最终我们要尝试的是让它以最好的方式发挥出来，如果我们把一切都投入其中
Even though it has an incredible story, in the end what we have to try is for it to play in the best way and if we put everything into it
por más que tenga una historia increíble al final nosotros lo que tenemos que intentar es que juegue de la mejor manera y si le ponemos toda
事情变得更加有趣。
even more spice to the matter.
todavía más pimienta al asunto.
简单，我的意思是，Gio 喜欢我使用它，抱歉，Ange，Gio 喜欢我使用它并且......
Easy, I mean, Gio liked me using it, sorry, Ange, Gio liked me using it and...
Fácil, digo, Gio le gustaba que la use, perdón, Ange, que le gustaba que la use a Gio y...
当我们到达酒店时，我们发现他们是这么说的。
And we found out when we arrived at the property that they said that.
Y nosotros nos enteramos cuando llegamos al predio, que dijeron eso.
对我们来说，完美。
And for us, perfect.
Y para nosotros, perfecto.
少了一个问题。
One less problem.
Un problema menos.
这里。
Here.
Aquí.
晚安。
Good night.
Buenas noches.
来自 Chubut 频道 12 和 FM del Viento 的 Augusto Arraquijar。
Augusto Arraquijar from Channel 12 of Chubut and FM del Viento.
Augusto Arraquijar de Canal 12 de Chubut y FM del Viento.
目标之一是不要加载卡牌，以免失去玩家，考虑到你已经失去了玩家。
One of the objectives was not to load cards so as not to lose players, taking into account that you had lost players.
Uno de los objetivos era no cargarse tarjetas para no perder jugadores teniendo en cuenta esto que habías perdido jugadores.
由于受伤，有 28 场比赛，如果你参加了两场比赛
due to injury there were 28 and if you took both games
por lesión que eran 28 y si tomaste los dos partidos
还用于准备
for the preparation of also
para la preparación de también
并进行轮换，或者你一场一场地考虑它，直到现在你才开始考虑哥伦比亚。
and make a rotation or you thought about it game by game and only now are you starting to think about Colombia.
y ir haciendo una rotación o lo pensaste partido a partido y recién ahora empezás a pensar en Colombia.
不不。
No no.
No, no.
我们从来没有考虑过今天出来的团队会考虑下一个团队。
We never think about the team that comes out today thinking about the next one.
Nunca pensamos el equipo que sale hoy pensando en el siguiente.
我的意思是，这支球队出来了
I mean, this team came out
O sea, salió este equipo
因为我们希望它是最好的。
because we wanted it to be the best.
porque queríamos que era el mejor.
是的，我们知道我们有四到五名黄色球员，但这就是这个，我们必须知道如何使用它，如果以后
and well yes we knew that we had four or five players with yellow but well that's what this has, we have to know how to play with it and if later
y bueno si sabíamos que teníamos cuatro o cinco jugadores con amarillas pero bueno es lo que tiene esto hay que saber jugar con eso y si después
谢谢大家！
Thank you all!
¡Gracias a todos!
缺席的事情发生了，最终我们缺席不是因为黄牌，也许是因为受伤，最终这与足球有关。
The thing about the absences happens, in the end we have absence not because of a yellow card, maybe because of an injury and in the end this is about football.
pasa lo de las bajas, al final tenemos baja no por amarilla, a lo mejor por lesión y al final esto es del fútbol.
我们希望在下一场比赛中恢复它们。
and we hope to recover them for the next game.
y esperemos recuperarlos para el siguiente partido.
但原则上我们选择将最好的球队放在黄色球队之外。
but in principle we chose to put the best team beyond the yellow ones.
pero en principio optamos por poner el mejor equipo más allá de las amarillas.
莱昂内尔，你好吗？
Lionel, how are you?
Lionel, ¿qué tal?
来自 Fútbol Pasión Permanente 的 Nicolás Tecchini，AM1010。
Nicolás Tecchini from Fútbol Pasión Permanente, AM1010.
Nicolás Tecchini de Fútbol Pasión Permanente, AM1010.
在某一时刻你改变了尼古拉斯·冈萨雷斯，他在左翼，
At one point you changed Nicolás González, he was in the left sector,
En un momento cambiaste Nicolás González, estaba por el sector izquierdo,
最后20分钟他踢的是右路，这或许是阿根廷队没有发挥出最佳状态的时刻。
In the last 20 minutes he played on the right side, which is perhaps where Argentina did not have its best moment.
en los últimos 20 minutos jugó por el sector derecho que a lo mejor es donde la Argentina no tuvo su mejor momento.
然后在下半场你决定让乔瓦尼·洛切尔佐上场。
and then in the second half you decided to put Giovanni Lochelzo on.
y después en segundo tiempo decidiste colocar a Giovanni Lochelzo.
考虑到他们在第二节的进步更大，你是否认为最好在中场打更多的比赛，让球队变得更有效率？
Did you think that it was best to play more in the middle would make the team more effective considering that they improved much more in the second?
¿Pensaste que lo mejor jugar más por el medio le daba más efectividad al equipo teniendo en cuenta que mejoró mucho más en el segundo?
关于第一个？
Regarding the first?
respecto al primero?
嗯，原则上，我们第一次看到这一点
Well, in principle, in the first time we saw that
Bueno, en principio, en el primer tiempo veíamos que
在莫利纳这边，我们可以有更多我们没有的深度，让尼科和纳韦尔包夹他
On Molina's side we could have a little more depth that we didn't have and putting Nico with Nahuel doubling him
por el lado de Molina podíamos tener un poco más de profundidad que no la teníamos y poniendo a Nico con Nahuel doblandolo
这可能是一个没有发生的选择，实际上它没有发生。
It could be an option that did not occur, in reality it did not occur.
podría ser una opción que no se dio, en la realidad no se dio.
第一次，我们决定回到最初的计划。
the first time and we decided to go back to the initial plan.
el primer tiempo y decidimos que volver al plan inicial.
然后当尼科要求改变时我们必须选择歌海娜作为我们的对手
and then when Nico asks for the change we have to choose Garnacho as our opponent
y después cuando nico pide el cambio tenemos para optar por garnacho por oponente
在那一刻我们认为这更多的是一场游戏控制比赛而不是那么多
and at that moment we thought it was more of a game control match and not so much
y en ese momento pensamos que era más un partido de control del juego y no tanto
疯狂。
be frenetic.
sea frenético.
因为那是我们获胜的时期，所以结果有点开放。
because it was a time when we were winning, the result was a bit open.
porque era un momento en que íbamos ganando, que estaba un poco ahí el resultado abierto.
然后当我们看到比赛朝着我们的方向发展时，我们把歌海娜
and then when we saw that the game was heading our way, we put Garnacho
y después cuando vimos que el partido se encaminaba para nuestro lado, metimos a Garnacho
他做了他所做的事情，这非常好，这就是解释。
He did what he did which was very good so that's kind of the explanation.
hizo lo que hizo que fue muy bueno así que un poco esa es la explicación
莱昂内尔，晚安，你好吗？
Leonel, good night, how are you?
Leonel, buenas noches, ¿cómo estás?
这是来自萨卢达的米努托拉科鲁尼亚队球员马蒂亚斯·巴苏尔多。
Here is Matías Basualdo from Saluda for Minuto Deportivo.
Acá Matías Basualdo de Saluda para Minuto Deportivo.
首先，祝贺胜利。
First, congratulations on the victory.
Primero, felicitaciones por la victoria.
我想问你对劳塔罗·马丁内斯和朱利安·阿尔瓦雷斯二人组有何看法。
I wanted to ask you what opinion you have regarding the duo, Lautaro Martínez, Julián Álvarez.
Te quería consultar qué opinión tenés al respecto de la dupla, Lautaro Martínez, Julián Álvarez.
你怎么看到的？
How did you see it?
¿Cómo lo viste?
你能做什么分析？
What analysis can you do?
¿Qué análisis podés hacer?
太感谢了。
Thank you so much.
Muchas gracias.
很好，他们互补，互相理解。
very good, they complement each other well, they understand each other well.
muy buena, se complementan bien, se entienden bien.
他们不会丢球，他们是...
They don't lose the ball, they are players who...
No van con la pelota por perdida, son jugadores que...
当他们打得这么好时，很难选择其中之一。
When they play this well it is difficult to choose one over the other.
que cuando juegan así de bien es difícil optar por uno por otro.
这就是现实。
and it is reality.
y es la realidad.
今天我们和他们两个一起踢球，我们很高兴。
We played with both of them today, we are happy.
Nosotros hoy jugamos con los dos, estamos contentos.
奥塔罗
The Autaro
El Autaro
他不仅打出了一场精彩的比赛，而且还提供了助攻。
Not only did he have a great game, he assisted.
No solo hizo un gran partido, asistió.
他处于球队的球门位置，而我们则是
He was in the team's goal situations and we are
estuvo en las situaciones de gol del equipo y estamos
对他的贡献感到满意，和朱利安一样，事实是，两人做出了
happy with his contribution and the same as Julián, the truth is that the two made a
contento con su aportación y lo mismo que Julián, la verdad que hicieron los dos un
非常完美的搭配，而且它们相得益彰。
very complete match and they complement each other well.
partido muy completo y se complementan bien.
有时，一个下降，另一个伸展，反之亦然。
There are times when one descends and the other stretches and vice versa.
Hay veces que desciende uno y el otro estira y viceversa.
这就是他们可以互补的好处。
That's the good thing that they can complement each other.
Eso es lo bueno que se pueden complementar.
莱昂内尔，晚安。
Lionel, good night.
Lionel, buenas noches.
路易斯·弗雷戈西 (Luis Fregosi) 来这里是为了……你好吗？
Luis Fregosi here to... How are you doing?
Luis Fregosi acá para... ¿Cómo te va?
布宜诺斯艾利斯广播电台 AM 1350、阿根廷世界广播电台。
for Radio Buenos Aires AM 1350, Mundo Argentina Radio.
para Radio Buenos Aires AM 1350, Mundo Argentina Radio.
我想问一下你所说的新来的孩子的情况。
I wanted to ask you about the situation of the new kids you are mentioning.
Te quería preguntar por la situación de los nuevos chicos que vas citando.
有可能排名越接近，
There is a chance that the closer the ranking is,
Hay una posibilidad de que mientras más cerca esté la clasificación,
在最近的比赛中，从一开始就有更多的机会看到他们。
In the last games there are more possibilities of seeing them from the start.
en los últimos partidos haya más posibilidades de verlos ya desde el arranque.
不仅整合了清单，今天你还必须留下一些......
not only integrating the list, today you had to leave some...
no solamente integrando la lista, hoy tuviste que dejar algunos...
显然，由于你提到的球员数量，在替补席之外。
outside the bench, obviously, due to the number of players you mention.
afuera del banco, obviamente, por la cantidad de jugadores que citás.
或许这个可以看出来
Maybe this can be seen
Quizás esto se pueda ver
选择已经接近分类。
with a selection already close to the classification.
con una selección ya cercana a la clasificación.
嗯，我不知道什么时候会发生，我希望它尽快发生，如果发生的话
Well, I don't know when that will happen, I hope it happens as soon as possible, and if it does
Bueno, no sé cuándo pasará eso, ojalá pase cuanto antes, y si pasa
我们的想法始终是，如果男孩们必须参加比赛，那是因为他们应得的。
Our idea is always that if the boys have to play it is because they deserve it.
siempre nuestra idea es si los chicos tienen que jugar es por merecimiento por
因为我们相信团队需要它
because we believe that the team needs it
porque creemos que el equipo lo necesita
如果发生这种情况，这就是我们要做的。
and that's what we're going to do if this happens.
y es lo que vamos a hacer si esto pasaría.
我认为我们不可能在一夜之间更换五六名球员。
We cannot change five or six players overnight, I think.
no podemos de la noche a la mañana cambiar cinco o seis jugadores creo que
我们很少见面，当我们见面时，我们需要每个人都感受到联系。
We see each other very little and when we see each other we need everyone to feel connected.
Nosotros nos vemos bastante poco y cuando nos vemos necesitamos que todo el mundo se sienta acoplado.
如果发生这种情况，我们肯定会给予几分钟的时间，并且......
We will surely give minutes if that happens and...
seguramente daremos minutos si eso pasa y...
我们有点超前了，但如果真的发生了，我们会给这些孩子一点时间，他们值得。
that we are getting ahead of ourselves, but if it happens, well, we will give these kids a minute who deserve it.
que nos estamos adelantando, pero si pasa, bueno, daremos un minuto a estos chicos que lo merecen.
还有关于他们必须离开的想法，我不是一点一点说的，但是当他们真的
Also about the idea that they have to go, I'm not saying little by little, but when they really
También sobre la idea de que tienen que ir, no digo poco a poco, pero cuando realmente
我认为他必须有机会，而不是给他机会或者这样说只是因为，因为
I think he has to have the opportunity, not give it to him or put it that way just because, because
creo que tiene que tener la oportunidad, no dársela o ponerlo así porque sí, porque
我们知道这件衬衫是什么，我们的想法是它们可以保留很长时间并且不会
We know what this shirt is and the idea is that they stay for a long time and do not
sabemos lo que es esta camiseta y la idea es que se queden por mucho tiempo y no
不，也许他会做错事，这就是我们正在努力做的。
No, maybe he'll do something wrong and that's what we're trying to do.
No, a lo mejor hacerle un mal y eso es lo que intentamos hacer.
莱昂内尔，晚安。
Lionel, good night.
Lionel, buenas noches.
首先，祝贺您取得胜利。
First of all, congratulations on the victory.
Primero que nada, felicidades por la victoria.
我是 FM Meraki 摇滚乐节目的伊万·莱瓦托 (Iván Levato)。
This is Iván Levato for Rock and Roll on FM Meraki.
Te habla Iván Levato para Rock and Roll por FM Meraki.
向他们询问所取得的一切成就以及如何传播这些成就。
Ask them questions about everything that has been achieved, how to transmit it.
hacerles consultas con todo lo que se ha logrado, cómo se hace para transmitir.
这仍然使球员的脚保持在地面上，如果其他更简单
that still keeps the players' feet on the ground and if the other simpler
que todavía mantenga los pies sobre la tierra a los jugadores y si la otra más sencilla
这支球队是否有上限，或者每次比赛时上限都会变大？
Is there a ceiling for this team or does that ceiling get larger every time it plays?
¿Hay techo para esta selección o cada vez que juega se va agrandando ese techo?
我之前或多或少回答了第一个问题。
I more or less answered the first question before.
La primera pregunta más o menos la respondí antes.
所做的就是传输...
What is done is transmit...
Lo que se hace es transmitir...
背后有队友在推动并想要比赛。
that there are teammates behind who are pushing and want to play.
que hay compañeros atrás que vienen empujando y quieren jugar.
以及一个不想玩的人。
and the one who doesn't feel like playing.
y el que no se siente con ganas de jugar.
我不需要告诉他，因为我立刻意识到，他不会在那里。
I don't need to tell him because I realize right away, he wouldn't be there.
que no hace falta decírselo porque me doy cuenta enseguida, no estaría.
他们没有表现出这一点，他们表现出了想要在那里的愿望。
They don't show that, they show the desire to want to be there.
No demuestran eso, demuestran las ganas de querer estar.
贡献的愿望
the desire to contribute
la gana de aportar
这是一个好兆头，当有一天我们出了问题时，就会达到上限
and that is a good sign and the ceiling will be when one day things go wrong for us
y eso es una buena señal y el techo será cuando un día nos vaya mal
将会发生什么，从那里看我们如何站起来。
What is going to happen and from there see how we get up.
que va a pasar y a raíz de ahí ver cómo nos levantamos.
我想也许我们会习惯现在的情况，但这种情况总会发生。
I think maybe we'll get used to the situation we're in, but it's going to happen.
creo que a lo mejor nos malacostumbramos de la situación que estamos pero va a pasar
当它发生时，好吧，站起来......
and when it happens, well, get back up and...
y cuando pase, bueno, volverse a levantar y...
这就是我们的想法，你并不总是会赢，这一点我们很清楚。
and that is the idea, you are not always going to win, that is clear to us.
y es esa la idea, no siempre se va a ganar, eso lo tenemos claro.
并且感觉非常好。
and feel very good.
y que se sienta muy bien.
并为可能发生的一切做好准备。
and be prepared for whatever comes.
y estar preparado para lo que venga.
但我们的想法是竞争，然后是比赛水平、上限等等……
But the idea is to compete, then the level of play, the ceiling and all that...
Pero la idea es competir, después el nivel de juego, el techo y todo eso ya...
这是一个不同的话题，每个人都可以发表自己的意见，是否可以给予更多。
It is a different topic and everyone can give their opinion on whether more can be given or not.
Es un tema diferente y cada uno puede opinar si se puede dar más o no.
最后一个问题。
Last question.
Ultima pregunta.
莱昂内尔，晚安。
Leonel, good night.
Leonel, buenas noches.
切洛·拉瓦莱 (Chelo Lavalle) 为更衣室进球。
Chelo Lavalle for the locker room goal.
Chelo Lavalle para gol del vestuario.
21分中取得18分。
18 of 21 points achieved.
18 de 21 puntos conseguidos.
为什么阿根廷队在预选赛中表现得如此轻松、如此复杂？
Why does Argentina make it so easy in the qualifiers, being as complicated as they are?
¿Por qué lo hace tan sencillo Argentina en las eliminatorias siendo tan complicadas como son?
布埃诺...
Bueno...
我认为球队对待每场比赛都好像......
I think the team approaches each game as if it were...
Creo que el equipo afronta cada partido como si fuera...
决赛
a final
una final.
绝对是全部。
Absolutely all.
Absolutamente todos.
对手并不重要，对手在哪里也不重要。
It doesn't matter the rival, it doesn't matter where.
Da igual el rival, da igual dónde.
我认为球员的素质很好，剩下的就完成了。
and good in the quality of the players I think that then does the rest.
y bueno en la calidad de los jugadores creo que después hace el resto.
对此的评论很简单，当他们以这种品质、这场胜利和这场比赛打球时，他们非常好
It is simple to comment on it, they are very good when they play with this quality and with this win and with this
es simple comentarlo ellos son muy buenos cuando juegan con esta calidad y con esta gana y con esta
理解足球的方式
way to understand football
manera de entender el fútbol
可能会出错，但你会留下一个好的形象。
It may go wrong but you will leave a good image.
te puede ir mal pero dejarás una buena imagen.
在这种情况下，进展并不顺利，而且......
In this case it is not going well and...
En este caso no está yendo bien y...
我认为关键在于如何处理每场比赛，以及他们打得很好的事实。
and I think the key is that, how each game is approached, added to the fact that they play well.
y creo que la clave es eso, cómo se afronta cada partido, sumado a que juegan bien.
谢谢莱昂内尔，谢谢大家，晚安。
Thank you Leonel, thank you all, good night.
Gracias Leonel, gracias a todos, buenas noches.